Okay so as you can see we have our plant pot here, it's been drying on our racks for a little while.
And we will see if it's, there we go, yes it's popped right off of there.
So now we can see what we have is a pot that is ready to be trimmed.
And to trim this pot I would like to quickly give some tips on how to make this a quick and easy process.
What I have here is just a regular bat on the wheel.
We can get different kinds of bats for trimming, some come with a piece of carpet or felt on top.
So that we can place a pot on and it won't slip around.
They also make what's called a giffen grip which has a gear inside it.
Which will center the pot for you as you turn the wheel.
However I just have a regular bat here that you'll find in any ceramic studio.
And to make my life easier, what I like to do is take a pencil and simply draw some concentric lines on the bat.
You can do this with water or different kinds.
Some bats come with rings already on them to help with this.
But as you can see I'm simply giving myself some concentric circles.
Now I'm going to take my plant pot and turn it upside down like this, and then take it down on to the bat and line it up with one of those circles.
This really does make life so much easier in the long run.
Because now we already have the pot basically centered on the wheel.
Okay so we have our pot on the wheel, turned upside down.
And we're ready to center this pot onto the wheel.
And I will be showing you how to do that next.